askvg.com 2019-05-22

# Privacy Policy - AskVG

We here at AskVG respect your privacy and we value your trust in us. Your privacy is of extreme importance to us and we are always committed to safeguarding it.

On this page we'll mention what personal information we collect and why we collect it, what rights you have over your data, what are cookies, what cookies we use, how can you disable or delete cookies, etc.

**Who we are**

AskVG is a technology website founded by Vishal Gupta who has been awarded with Microsoft MVP (Most Valuable Professional) award.

Our website address is: <https://www.askvg.com/>

**What personal data we collect and why we collect it  
**

AskVG.com does not collect any personally-identifiable information about you such as your name, address, phone number or email ID without your knowledge. When you provide your email ID while posting a comment or contacting us using contact page, we never share it with anyone. Your email ID will only be used for responding to your email or comment if requested and will never be made publicly available.

You can leave comments on this site and may do so completely anonymously. When you leave comments on the site, we collect the data shown in the comments form. You may (but don't have to) use your real email ID or name. We don't associate IP addresses with comments or store them.

**Who we share your data with**

We do not share or sell any personal data with anyone.

**How long we retain your data**

If you leave a comment, the comment, your name and email ID are retained indefinitely until we manually remove the older comments from our site to reduce database overhead. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

**What rights you have over your data**

If you have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes. If you want to delete one or more comments made by you on article pages of this website due to privacy reasons, you can request us and we'll remove your comments within 24 hours. You can also ask us to change your name or email ID used for posting a comment and we'll change it as per request. Note that you'll need to provide your email ID to link data to you.

Similarly if you are subscribed to our email newsletter and want to unsubscribe, you can do that anytime by using the unsubscribe link given in the newsletter. You can also contact us to remove the subscription and we'll manually remove your newsletter subscription. Once you unsubscribe, your email address is removed and no email record will be kept.

**Where we send your data**

Visitor information such as IP address and comments are checked through our security mechanisms (firewall and automated spam detection service) for a legitimate interest to secure and protect this website from spam and hacking attempts and based on these check results, the user is allowed or denied to access this website.

**Cookies and your consent**

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name and email address in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment.

Like other websites, we also use Google Analytics service to understand the traffic coming towards our website and to make our website better. It helps us in understanding how visitors use our website so that we can improve their experience. It just let us know how many visitors are coming from Desktops or mobile phones, how many visitors are using Windows operating system or Linux or Mac OS and other similar things. These statistics help us in understanding how we can improve the site for our readers. The collected information is anonymous so we don't know who you are. It's like somebody visited our website. None of this information can personally identify specific visitors to this site. We use Google Analytics with anonymized IP feature which prevents Google from storing visitors full IP address. We have also configured Google Analytics to use the lowest period of time for which data that is collected is associated with cookies and user identifiers. If you wish, you can opt-out of the analytics feature using this official [browser add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout) provided by Google.

We use third-party advertisements on this website such as Google AdSense to pay hosting server bills and to keep this website functional and running. These ad companies can use cookies or web beacons to collect some information about your visit to serve ads of interest to you. You can manage, delete or turn them off any time using your web browser settings. You can also opt-out of the use of DART cookie by Google using [this link](https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads).

You can visit [Google's privacy policy page](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites) to learn more about Google services.

By using our site, you consent to our use of cookies. Remember cookies are automatically stored by your web browser whenever you visit any website. Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer to help a site distinguish you from other users and provide a better and easier user experience. In general, cookies are used to retain user preferences, store information and provide anonymized tracking data to third party applications like Google Analytics. As a rule, cookies will make your browsing experience better.

However, you may withdraw your consent at any time. If you do not wish to accept cookies, you'll need to clear or block cookies on this site and on others. The most effective way to do this is to disable cookies in your web browser settings but remember it might prevent some pages from displaying correctly and might affect many websites functionality such as login to email services, websites and forums, etc. Many websites require cookies to function properly. If you don't want to disable cookies, you can use your browser settings page to clear/delete existing cookies created by a website. You can take help of [this tutorial](https://www.askvg.com/tip-how-to-clear-delete-cache-and-cookies-in-your-web-browser/) to learn more about clearing cookies in all popular web browsers. You can also set your web browser to automatically clear/delete cookies when you close the browser. The options to change cookies settings are generally found in the "Options" or "Preferences" menu of your web browser. You can also use the "Help" option in your web browser to learn more about cookies settings.

**Changes to privacy policy**

Although most changes are likely to be minor, we may change our privacy policy from time to time, and at our sole discretion. If we decide to make changes to our privacy policy, we'll post those changes on this page. We encourage visitors to periodically check this page to ensure you are familiar with the most current version. Your continued use of this site after any change in this privacy policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.

**Contact information**

If you still have doubts or questions, please feel free to [contact us](https://www.askvg.com/contact/) for any questions or concerns regarding your privacy.
